(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
別世界
Amane Kanata 3rd Anniversary LIVE
Another World
ライブ中に重大発表あり!
Major announcement during the live!
Kanata Amane 3rd Anniversary
天音かなた
Amane Kanata
3周年記念ライブ
3rd Anniversary LIVE
別世界
Another World
ヒビカセ
作詞：Reol 作曲：Giga
Hibikase
Lyrics: Reol Composition: Giga
真夜中に告ぐ 音の警告
Sounding the midnight warning
協和音に酔う 午前0時
Intoxicated by harmony at midnight
あなたが触れる 光、増す熱
The light you touch, the increasing heat
指先に躍らされ
Dancing at your fingertips
感覚 即 体感
Sensation, immediate experience
寝静まる夜 二人だけの密事
A quiet night, a secret just for the two of us
感覚 即 体感
Sensation, immediate experience
重なる波形に 魅了されていく
Captivated by the overlapping waveforms
忘れないでね 私の声を
Don't forget my voice
画面越しでいい ちゃんと愛して
Through the screen is fine, love me properly
バーチャルだって 突き放さないで
Don't push me away just because I'm virtual
あなたの音に 今は溺れていたい
I want to drown in your sound right now
覚えていてね 私の声を
Remember my voice
あなたがくれた この身すべてを
All of this body you gave me
見つめていてね あなたと二人
Keep watching me, just the two of us
重ねた息を そっと響かせ
Let our overlapping breaths softly echo
真夜中に問う 冷え切った熱
Questioning the chilled heat in the middle of the night
待ち続けてる 午前0時
Still waiting at midnight
鏡越しに 綻んでいく
Unraveling through the mirror
知らない音が伝う
An unknown sound travels along
感覚 即 体感
Sensation, immediate experience
寝静まる夜と 吐息重なり
Overlapping breaths with the quiet night
感覚 即 体感
Sensation, immediate experience
錆びたロジック 今一度溶かせ
Melt the rusted logic once more
忘れないでね 私の声を
Don't forget my voice
ヒビカセ
Hibikase
紛れ込んで　飛ばすシグナル
Merging in, sending out signals
バーチャルなんて言わないで
Don't say it's just virtual
あなたの音に　まだ愛されていたい
I still want to be loved by your sound
覚えていてね　私の声を
Please remember my voice
あなたがくれた　この身すべてを
Everything about this body you gave me
言の葉と　はずの音が交わる
Words and the sound of my breath intertwine
この息と　音響かせ
Let this breath and sound resonate
あぁ　あなたの産んだ音に
Ah, in the sound you created
あぁ　恋をしていたの
Ah, I was in love
悲しみ　怒り　感謝すべて
Sadness, anger, gratitude, everything
打ち鳴らす
Resonating
絶えず叫ぶ　声連ねる
Ceaselessly shouting, stringing voices together
余熱混ぜる　相槌やめ
Mixing residual heat, stop nodding
巡る
Circulating
絶えず叫ぶ　声連ねる
Ceaselessly shouting, stringing voices together
余熱混ぜる　相槌やめ
Mixing residual heat, stop nodding
巡る
Circulating
魅了されていく
Being captivated
忘れないでね　私の声を
Don't forget my voice
画面の向こう　ちゃんと愛して
Love me properly beyond the screen
バーチャルなんて　突き放さないで
Don't push me away saying I'm virtual
あなたの音に　まだ溺れていたい
I still want to be drowned in your sound
覚えていてね　私の声を
Please remember my voice
あなたがくれた　この身すべてを
Everything about this body you gave me
見つめ合う　あなたと二人重ねて
Gazing at each other, our two selves overlapping
息と音響かせ
Let our breath and sound resonate
あなたのはずの音　この声聞かせ
Let me hear your breath and this voice
音響かせ
Make the sound resonate
私の恋を悲劇のジュリエットにしないで
Don't make my love a tragic Juliet
ここから連れ出して…
Take me away from here...
そんな気分よ
That's how I feel
ロミオとシンデレラ 作詞・作曲: doriko
Romeo and Cinderella Lyrics/Composition: doriko
パパとママにおやすみなさい
Say goodnight to Papa and Mama
せいぜい良い夢を見なさい
Dream a good dream as best as you can
大人はもう寝る時間よ
It's time for adults to go to bed
むせ返る魅惑のキャラメル
Suffocating, enchanting caramel
恥じらいの素足を絡める
Entwining shy bare feet
今夜はどこまで行けるの？
How far can we go tonight?
噛みつかないで　優しくして
Don't bite, be gentle
苦いものはまだ嫌いなの
I still hate bitter things
ママの作るお菓子ばかり食べたせいね
It's because I only ate the sweets Mama made
知らないことがあるのならば　知りたいと思う　普通でしょ？
If there's something I don't know, it's normal to want to know, right?
全部見せてよ　あなたにならば
Show me everything, if it's you
見せてあげる　私の…
I'll show you mine...
ずっと恋しくてシンデレラ
Always longing, Cinderella
制服だけで駆けていくわ
I'll run with just my uniform
魔法よ時間を止めてよ
Magic, please stop time
悪い人に邪魔されちゃうわ
Bad people will get in the way
逃げ出したいのジュリエット
I want to escape, Juliet
でもその名前で呼ばないで
But don't call me by that name
そうよね結ばれなくちゃね　そうじゃないと楽しくないわ
That's right, we have to be together, otherwise it's not fun
ねえ　私と生きてくれる？
Hey, will you live with me?
背伸びをした長いマスカラ
Tip-toed, long mascara
いい子になるわ　きっと明日から
I'll be a good girl, starting tomorrow for sure
今だけ私を許して
Just for now, forgive me
黒いレースの境界線
Black lace boundary line
守る人は今日は居ません
There's no one to protect me today
越えたらどこまで行けるの？
If I cross it, how far can we go?
噛みつくほどに　痛いほどに　好きになってたのは私でしょ
I was the one who fell in love enough to bite, enough to hurt, right?
パパはでもねあなたのこと嫌いみたい
But you know, Papa seems to hate you
私のためと差し出す手に握ってるそれは首輪でしょ
The hand reached out 'for my sake' is holding a collar, isn't it?
連れ出してよ私のロミオ
Take me away, my Romeo
叱られるほど遠くへ
To somewhere far enough to be scolded
鐘が鳴り響くシンデレラ
The bells ring out, Cinderella
ガラスの靴は置いていくわ
I'll leave the glass slipper behind
だからね早く見つけてね
So please, find me quickly
あわよくばきっとあの娘も染まった
If lucky, surely that girl too was tainted
落としたなんて嘘ついて
Saying "I dropped it" as a lie
そうよね私も同じよ
That's right, I'm the same
だってもっと愛されたいわ
Because I want to be loved even more
ほら私はここにいるよ
Look, I am right here
私の心そっと覗いてみませんか
Would you like to take a peek at my heart?
欲しいものだけあふれかえっていませんか
Isn't it overflowing with only the things you want?
まだ別腹よもっともっとぎゅっと詰め込んで
I still have room, pack it in tighter and tighter
いっそあなたの居場所まで埋めてしまおうか
Shall I even go so far as to bury your place too?
でもそれじゃ意味ないの
But that would be meaningless
大きな箱より小さな箱に幸せはあるらしい
It seems happiness is in a small box rather than a large one
どうしようこのままじゃ私はあなたに嫌われちゃうわ
What should I do? At this rate, I'll be hated by you
でも私より欲張りなパパとママは今日も変わらず
But Papa and Mama, greedier than me, are the same today as ever
そうよね素直でいいのね
That's right, it's okay to be honest
落としたのは金の斧でした
What I dropped was a golden axe
嘘つきすぎたシンデレラ オオカミに食べられたらしい
Cinderella, who lied too much, seems to have been eaten by a wolf
どうしようこのままじゃ私もいつかは食べられちゃうわ
What should I do? At this rate, I too will be eaten someday
あ、その前に助けに来てね
Ah, before that, come save me
ジッタードール 作詞・作曲niki
Jitter Doll - Lyrics & Composition: niki
雨上がる途中の雫眺めて
Watching the droplets as the rain stops
右目にコネクタ繋ぐ動力
Power connecting the connector to my right eye
乱れ 乱れ この温度で全て溶けるような
Disordered, disordered, as if everything would melt at this temperature
飛ばせ 飛ばせ 滅ぶまで悲しみの世界へ
Fly away, fly away, to the world of sorrow until it perishes
そして操られる その世界に何が見える
And being manipulated, what do you see in that world?
異常なほどに境界線がない 意志は
The will, which strangely has no boundaries
人はそう それを愛とまだ呼んでいる
People still call that love
その愛を産みながら 愛し合う世界では
In a world where they love each other while birthing that love
愛が与えられないものがいないと
There is no one who isn't given love
繰り返す歴史をインストールして
Installing the repeating history
青白く塗れよ 響く雷鳴
Paint it pale white, the echoing thunder
繋げ 繋げ このコードで争いの世界へ
Connect, connect, with this cord to the world of conflict
染まれ 染まれ パラサイトで血液の中まで
Be stained, be stained, by the parasite into the blood
そして何が見える それは空を砕く光
And what do you see? It is the light that shatters the sky
狂うほどに不確定な動力 意志は
The will, the power so uncertain it's maddening
人はそう それを命とまだ呼んでいる
People still call that life
その命を守りながら 奪い合う世界では
In a world where they snatch away while protecting that life
涙流して嘆くものがいないと
There is no one who sheds tears and laments
信じて
Believe
雨上がる空に希望の跡
Traces of hope in the rain-cleared sky
咲いた水溜り 鼓動の跡
A puddle blossomed, traces of a heartbeat
起きてよ 起きてよ
Wake up, wake up
錆びついた歯車が回りだす 繋がって
The rusted gears start to turn, connected
愛を待つ生命を 人はそう 人とまだ呼んでいる
Life that waits for love, people still call it human
素晴らしい世界では
In a wonderful world,
涙流して嘆く者はいないと
They say no one sheds tears or laments...
異常な
Abnormal,
視界恋愛図を人は
That map of blind love,
そっ空を神とまだ呼んでいる
People still call it God.
その神を信じながら
While believing in that God,
救われる世界では
In a world that is saved,
声を枯らして嘆く者はいないと
They say no one cries out until their voice is parched.
信じて
Believe...
はい！ えー、お送りいたしましたのは…
Yes! Uh... what I've presented...
違う、お聞きいただきましたのは
No, what you've just heard was
えー、『ヒビカセ』、『ロミオとシンデレラ』、
そして『ジッタードール』でございました！
uh... 'Hibikase', 'Romeo and Cinderella',
and 'Jitter Doll'!
ということで、みんな！ ヘーイ！ こんかなたー！
And so, everyone! Hey! Kon-Kanata!
キャッチコピーは握力50キロ、ギュッギュッ、握り潰しちゃうぞ！
My catchphrase is 'Grip strength 50kg, squeeze squeeze, I'll crush you!'
ホロライブ4期生かなたんこと、天音かなたです！
I'm Kanatan, a.k.a. Amane Kanata from Hololive's 4th Generation!
本日はですね、天音かなた3周年記念ライブ
Today is... Amane Kanata's 3rd Anniversary Memorial Live.
天音かなた3周年記念ライブにお越しくださりありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for coming to Amane Kanata's 3rd Anniversary Memorial Live!
ぜひね、ハッシュタグでツイ…ツイートいっぱいしてください！
Please tweet a lot with the hashtag!
たくさんね、あの、スクショとかも待っておりますので、ぜひよろしくお願いします！
I'm also looking forward to lots of screenshots, so please do!
はい。あの、非常にね、主張の激しい
Yes. This is Amane Kanata's very intense
天音かなた3周年アニバーサリー記念ライブの『別世界』ということで
3rd Anniversary Memorial Live, 'Another World'...
別世界、別世界です。覚えて帰ってください。
...'Another World', 'Another World'. Please remember that.
ということでですね、ちょっとお着替えをしたいと思います。
So now, I'd like to change my outfit for a bit.
見ないで！ やだやだ！
Don't look! No, no!
見ちゃダメだってば！ はっ！
I said don't look! Hah!
おっ！ バーチャルの着替えって簡単だな！
Oh! Changing outfits in virtual reality is so easy!
ということで、このままもうどんどん歌っていきたいと思います！
So, I'd like to keep on singing just like this!
それでは次の曲はですね、『歌ってみた』でも投稿している
Well then, the next song is one I've also uploaded a cover of,
みんなの大好きな、元気になれるあの曲です！
that energetic song everyone loves!
では聴いてください、『テレキャスタービーボーイ』！
Now please listen to... 'Telecaster B-Boy'!
One, two, three, four!
大人になるほどデ・デ・デ はみだしものですガランド
The more I grow up, the more of an outcast I become. It's empty.
偽理論じゃ語った少女は鳥になって
The girl who spoke of false theories turned into a bird.
綺麗事だけでパ・パ・パ ボロボロの靴を結んで
With just empty words, I tie up my worn-out shoes.
デジタル信者が祟った少年は風になって
The boy who stood as a digital believer turned into the wind.
ゆらりくらり大往生 お疲れ様ですご臨終
Swaying and wandering, I'm okay. Good job, and rest in peace.
テレキャスタービーボーイ 僕に愛情を
Telecaster B-Boy, give me affection.
嘘で固めたウォーアイニー
In a deep love hardened with lies.
うざったいんだ直貼りハイテンション
It's annoying, this high tension directly applied.
カニバリズム踊れば
If we dance to cannibalism,
一つ二つ殺めた手で
One by one, with these murderous hands,
何を描いているんだろう
What exactly am I drawing?
テレキャスタービーボーイ 僕に愛情を
Telecaster B-Boy, give me affection.
誰か答えてくれないか
Won't someone please answer me?
見た目がどうやらデ・デ・デ 捨てるバイアス サイコシスティック
Apparently, my appearance is... discarding biases, psychocitric.
毒針持ったように歌った少女は花になって
The girl who sang as if holding a poisonous needle turned into a flower.
耳を塞いでもパ・パ・パ 奴らの声は針になって
Even if I plug my ears, their voices turn into needles.
胸に刺さったあの言葉 少年は振り返って
Those words that pierced my chest... the boy looks back.
ゆらりくらり大妄想 お互い様ですご臨終
Swaying and wandering, a great delusion. It's mutual, rest in peace.
テレキャスタービーボーイ 僕に感情を
Telecaster B-Boy, give me emotions.
ノイズ混じりのウォーアイニー
In a deep love mixed with noise.
じれったいんだ御油断禁物さ
It's frustrating, you mustn't let your guard down.
頬に溶けた涙痕を
The teardrop trace that melted on my cheek,
忘れたくて喉を締めた
I wanted to forget, so I tightened my throat.
過去に残した傷跡
The scars I left in the past.
テレキャスタービーボーイ 僕に感情を
Telecaster B-Boy, give me emotions.
今だけ抱いてくれないか
Won't you embrace me just for now?
こんな世界じゃもう息ができないって
Saying I can't breathe in a world like this anymore,
さよなら告げた現実に
To the reality I said goodbye to.
許してくれないか 弱い僕たちを
Won't you forgive our weak selves?
またどこかで会いましょう
Let's meet again somewhere.
テレキャスタービーボーイ 僕に愛情を
Telecaster B-Boy, give me affection.
嘘で固めたウォーアイニー
In a deep love hardened with lies.
うざったいんだ直貼りハイテンション
It's annoying, this high tension directly applied.
カニバリズム踊れば
If we dance to cannibalism,
一つ二つ殺めた手で
One by one, with these murderous hands,
何を描いているんだろう
What exactly am I drawing?
テレキャスタービーボーイ 僕に愛情を
Telecaster B-Boy, give me affection.
誰か答えてくれないか
Won't someone please answer me?
パルラルラ
Paluralura
メルト
作詞・作曲 ryo
Melt
Lyrics & Composition: ryo
さあ目が覚めて
Now, I wake up
真っ先に思い浮かぶ
The first thing that comes to mind
君のこと
Is you
思い切って
Taking the plunge,
前髪を切った
I cut my bangs
どうしたのって
"What happened?"
聞かれたくて
I want you to ask me that
ピンクのスカート
My pink skirt,
お花の髪飾り
The flower hair ornament
さして出かけるの
I put them on and head out
今日の
Today,
私は
I am
かわいいのよ
so cute!
メルト
Melt,
溶けてしまいそう
I feel like I'm melting
好きだなんて
That I love you,
絶対に言えない
I can never say that
だけど
But,
メルト
Melt,
目も合わせられない
I can't even make eye contact
恋に恋なんて
Being in love with love...
しないわ
I don't do that,
わたし
not me
だって
Because
君のことが
it's you
好きなの
that I love
天気予報が
The weather forecast
ウソをついた
was wrong
土砂降りの雨が
It's raining cats and dogs
降る
now
カバンに入れたままの
The folding umbrella
オリタタミ傘
left in my bag
うれしくない
It doesn't make me happy
ためいきをついた
I let out a sigh
そんなとき
Just then,
「しょうがないから
"Since there's no choice,
入ってやる」なんて
I'll let you in (under my umbrella),"
隣にいる
Next to me,
君が笑う
you smile
恋に落ちる
Falling in love,
音がした
I heard the sound
メルト
Melt,
息が詰まりそう
I feel like I'm suffocating
君に触れてる
Touching you,
右手がふるえる
my right hand is shaking
高鳴る胸
My racing heart,
半分の傘
sharing this umbrella
手を伸ばせば
If I reach out,
届く距離
you're within reach
どうしよう
What should I do?
想いよ届け
Please, let my feelings reach you
君に
to you
お願い
Please,
時間を止めて
stop time
泣きそうなの
I feel like I'm going to cry
でも
But
うれしくて
I'm so happy
死んでしまうわ
I'm going to die
メルト
Melt,
駅に着いてしまう
we've arrived at the station
もう会えない
We can't meet anymore,
近くて
so close
遠いよ
yet so far
だから
So,
メルト
Melt,
手をつないで歩きたい
I want to walk holding hands
もうバイバイ
It's time to say goodbye,
しなくちゃいけないの
I have to do it
今すぐわたしを
Right now, me,
抱きしめて
hold me tight
なんてね
Just kidding
少女レイ
Shoujo Rei
作詞・作曲 みきとP
Lyrics & Composition: Mikito-P
本能が狂い始める
Instinct starts to go mad
追い詰められたハツカネズミ
A cornered mouse
今 絶望の淵に立って
Standing now on the edge of despair
踏切へと飛び出した
I jumped towards the railroad crossing
そう、君は友達
That's right, you're a friend
僕の手を掴めよ
Grab my hand
そう、君は一人さ
That's right, you're alone
居場所なんて無いだろ
You don't have a place to belong, right?
二人きりこのまま
Just the two of us, like this
愛し合えるさ
We can love each other
繰り返すフラッシュバック
Repeating flashbacks
蝉の声
The sound of cicadas
二度と帰らぬ君
You, who will never return
永遠に千切れてく
Tearing apart forever
お揃いのキーホルダー
Matching keychains
夏が消し去った
Summer erased it all
白い肌の少女に
To the girl with white skin
哀しいほど取り憑かれてしまいたい
I want to be possessed by her, almost sadly
本性が暴れ始める
True nature starts to run wild
9月のスタート告げるチャイム
The chime announcing the start of September
次の標的に置かれた花瓶
The vase placed for the next target
仕掛けたのは僕だった
I was the one who set it up
そう、君が悪いんだよ
That's right, it's your fault
僕だけを見ててよ
Look only at me
そう、君の苦しみ
That's right, your suffering
助けたかったろ
You wanted to be saved, right?
溺れてくその手に
To that hand that's drowning
そっとキスをした
I gave a gentle kiss
薄笑いの獣たち
The faintly smiling beasts
その心晴れるまで
Until that heart clears up
爪を突き立ててる
Sinking its claws in
不揃いのスカート
The uneven skirt
夏の静寂を
The silence of summer
切り裂くような悲鳴が
A scream like it's tearing apart
木霊する教室の窓には青空
Resonating in the classroom, blue sky through the window
君は友達
You are a friend
そう、君は友達
That's right, you're a friend
僕の手を掴めよ
Grab my hand
そう、君がいなくちゃ
That's right, without you
居場所なんて無いんだよ
I have no place to belong
透き通った世界で
In a transparent world
愛し合えたら
If we could love each other
繰り返すフラッシュバック
Repeating flashbacks
蝉の声
The sound of cicadas
二度と帰らぬ君
You, who will never return
永遠に千切れてく
Tearing apart forever
お揃いのキーホルダー
Matching keychains
夏が消し去った
Summer erased it all
白い肌の少女に
To the girl with white skin
哀しいほど取り憑かれてしまいたい
I want to be possessed by her, almost sadly
透明な君は僕を指差してた
The transparent you was pointing at me
La la la la...
「昨日人を殺したんだ」
"I killed someone yesterday"
君はそう言っていた
That's what you were saying
梅雨時 ずぶ濡れのまま部屋の前で泣いていた
During the rainy season, you were crying in front of the room, soaking wet
夏が始まったばかりだというのに 君はひどく震えていた
Even though summer had only just begun, you were shivering terribly
そんな話で始まる あの夏の日の記憶だ
It's a memory of that summer day that starts with such a story
あの夏が飽和する。
That summer becomes saturated.
昨日、人を殺したんだ。
Yesterday, I killed someone.
隣の席の、いつもいじめてくるあいつ。
That guy in the seat next to mine who was always bullying me.
もう嫌になって、肩を突き飛ばして、
I'd finally had enough and shoved his shoulder,
打ち所が悪かったんだ。
and he just hit the wrong spot.
もうここにはいられないし、
I can't stay here anymore,
どっか遠いとこで死んでくるよ。
so I'm going to die somewhere far away.
そんな君に僕は言った。
I said to you then,
「それじゃ僕も連れてって」
"In that case, take me with you."
財布を持って、ナイフを持って、
Taking my wallet, taking a knife,
携帯ゲームも鞄に詰めて。
and stuffing my handheld game into my bag.
いらないものは全部壊していこう。
Let's destroy everything we don't need.
あの写真も、あの日記も、
That photo, that diary,
今となっちゃもういらないさ。
they're all useless now.
人殺しと駄目人間。
A murderer and a good-for-nothing.
君と僕の旅だ。
This is your and my journey.
そして僕らは逃げ出した。
And so we ran away.
この狭い狭いこの世界から。
From this small, small world.
家族もクラスの奴らも、何もかも全部捨てて君と二人で。
Leaving behind family and classmates, leaving everything behind, just the two of us.
遠い遠い誰もいない場所で二人で死のう。
In a far, far place where no one else is, let's die together.
もうこの世界に価値などないよ。
There's no longer any value in this world.
人殺しなんてそこら中湧いてるじゃんか。
Murderers are popping up everywhere anyway.
君は何も悪くないよ。
You haven't done anything wrong.
結局僕ら誰にも愛されたことなどなかったんだ。
In the end, neither of us had ever been loved.
そんな嫌な共通点で僕らは簡単に信じ合ってきた。
With that unpleasant commonality, we easily came to trust each other.
君の手を握った時、微かな震えも既になくなっていて。
When I held your hand, even that slight trembling was already gone.
誰にも縛られないで二人、線路の上を歩いた。
Bound by no one, the two of us walked along the train tracks.
金を盗んで二人で逃げて、どこへでも行ける気がしたんだ。
Stealing money and running away together, I felt like we could go anywhere.
今更怖いものは僕らにはなかったんだ。
There was nothing left for us to be afraid of now.
額の汗も、落ちた眼鏡も、今となっちゃどうでもいいさ。
The sweat on our brows, the glasses that fell off, none of it matters now.
溢れ者の小さな、
The small flight from reality
逃避行の旅だ。
of two outcasts.
いつか夢見た優しくて、誰にでも好かれる主人公なら。
If I were the kind, well-liked protagonist I once dreamed of...
汚くなった僕たちも見捨てずにちゃんと救ってくれるのかな。
Would they save even us, who've become so stained, without abandoning us?
そんな夢はもう捨てたよ。だって現実を見ろよ。幸せは...
I've already thrown away such dreams. Because look at reality. Happiness is...
四文字なんてなかったんだ。今までの人生で思い知ったじゃないか。
That four-character word didn't exist. Haven't we learned that through our lives?
自分は何も悪くないと、誰もがきっと思ってる。
Everyone surely thinks that they haven't done anything wrong.
宛てもなく彷徨う、蝉の群れに。
Wandering aimlessly among swarms of cicadas.
水も無くなり、揺れ出す視界に。
Running out of water, my vision begins to waver.
迫り来る、鬼たちの怒号に。
Amidst the approaching roars of demons.
馬鹿みたいにはしゃぎ合い、ふと君はナイフを取った。
Foolishly making merry together, you suddenly picked up a knife.
君が今まで傍にいたから、ここまで来れたんだ。
It's because you were by my side until now that I was able to make it this far.
だからもういいよ。もういいよ。
So it's okay now. It's okay.
死ぬのは私一人でいいよ。
I should be the only one to die.
そして君は首を切った。
And then you slit your throat.
まるで何かの映画のワンシーンだ。
It was just like a scene from some movie.
白昼夢を見ている気がした。
I felt like I was having a daydream.
気付けば僕は捕まって。
Next thing I knew, I was caught.
君がどこにも見つからなくって、
And I couldn't find you anywhere,
君だけがどこにもいなくって。
you were the only one nowhere to be found.
そして時は過ぎて行った。あの暑い暑い日が過ぎて行った。
And so time passed by. Those hot, hot days passed by.
家族もクラスの奴らもいるのに、何故か君だけがどこにもいない。
Family and classmates are still around, yet for some reason, only you are nowhere to be found.
あの夏の日のことを思い出す。僕は今も今でも歌ってる。
I remember that summer day. I'm still singing even now.
君をずっと探しているんだ。君に言いたいことがあるんだ。
I'm searching for you always. There's something I want to tell you.
九月の終わりにくしゃみして、
Sneezing at the end of September,
六月の雨の匂いを繰り返す。
repeating the scent of the June rain.
君の笑顔は、君の無邪気さは、頭の中を飽和している。
Your smile, your innocence, they saturate my mind.
誰も何も悪くないよ。
No one did anything wrong.
君は何も悪くないから。
Because you haven't done anything wrong.
もういいよ、投げ出してしまおう。そう言って欲しかったのだろう。
It's okay now, let's just give it all up. That must have been what you wanted someone to say.
悪魔の子
作詞・作曲: ヒグチアイ
Akuma no Ko
Written and Composed by Higuchi Ai
鉄の弾が正義の証明 つらぬけば英雄に近づいた
Iron bullets are proof of justice.
If I fire them through, I get closer to being a hero.
その目を閉じて 触れてみれば 同じ形 同じ体温の悪魔
If you close your eyes and touch it,
you'll find a devil with the same shape and body temperature.
僕はダメで あいつはいいの?
Why am I no good, but they are?
そこに壁があっただけなのに 生まれてしまった 定め嘆くな
Even though there was just a wall there,
don't lament the fate of being born.
僕らはみんな 自由なんだから
Because we are all free.
鳥のように 羽があれば
If I had wings like a bird,
どこへだって 行けるけど
I could go anywhere,
帰る場所が なければきっと
but if I have no place to return to, I surely
どこへも 行けない
can't go anywhere.
ただただ生きるのは 嫌だ
I hate just living.
世界は残酷だ
The world is cruel.
それでも君を愛すよ
Even so, I will love you.
何を犠牲にしても
No matter what I have to sacrifice.
それでも君を守るよ
Even so, I will protect you.
間違いだとしても 疑ったりしない
Even if it's a mistake, I won't doubt it.
正しさとは 自分のこと 強く信じることだ
Righteousness is believing in yourself strongly.
鉄の雨が降りちる情景 テレビの中 映画に見えたんだ
The scene of iron rain falling down
looked like a movie on TV.
戦争なんて愚かな凶暴 関係ない 知らない国の話
War is such foolish violence. It's a story of a
country I don't know, nothing to do with me.
それならなんで あいつに組んで 黒い気持ち 隠しきれないわけ
If so, then why do I hate them?
Why can't I hide these dark feelings?
説明だって できやしないんだ 僕らはなんて不純なんだ
I can't even explain it.
We are so impure.
この言葉も 訳されれば
If these words are translated...
本当の意味は 伝わらない
...their true meaning won't get across.
信じるのは その目を開いて
All I believe in is...
触れた世界だけ
...the world I touched with my eyes open.
世界は残酷だ
The world is cruel.
それそれでも君を愛すよ
Even so, I will love you.
何を犠牲にしても
No matter what I have to sacrifice.
それそれでも君を守るよ
Even so, I will protect you.
選んだ人の影 捨てたものの屍
The shadow of the person I chose,
the corpses of the things I discarded.
気づいたんだ 自分の中 育つのは悪魔の子
I realized it. What grows inside me
is the child of evil.
正義の裏 犠牲の中 心には悪魔の子
Behind justice, amidst sacrifice,
there's a child of evil in my heart.
教えて 教えてよ その仕組みを
Tell me, tell me how it works.
unravel
作詞・作曲: TK
Written and Composed by TK
僕の中に 誰かいるの?
Is there someone inside me?
壊れた 壊れたよ この世界で
It's broken, it's broken, in this world...
君が笑う
...you are laughing.
なにも見えずに
Without being able to see anything
壊れた僕なんてさ
I'm just a broken person
息を止めて
Holding my breath
ほどけない もう ほどけないよ
Can't unwrap it, I can't unwrap it anymore
真実さえ
Not even the truth
Freeze
壊せる
I can break it
壊せない
I can't break it
狂える
I can go crazy
狂えない
I can't go crazy
あなたを見つけて
I've found you
揺れて歪んだ世界にだんだん
In this swaying, distorted world,
僕は
I'm gradually...
透き通って見えなくなって
becoming transparent and invisible
見つけないで
Don't find me
僕のことを見つめないで
Don't gaze at me
誰かが描いた世界の中で
In the world someone else envisioned
あなたを傷つけたくはないよ
I don't want to hurt you
覚えていて
Remember me
僕のことを
For who I am
鮮やかなまま
As vivid as can be
無限に広がる孤独が絡まる
An infinite loneliness entangles me
無邪気に笑った記憶が刺さって
Memories of innocent laughter pierce through
動けない 動けない 動けない 動けない 動けない 動けないよ
I can't move, I can't move, I can't move, I can't move, I can't move, I can't move!
変わってしまった
Everything has changed
変えられなかった
Nothing could be changed
二つが絡まる
The two become entangled
二人が滅びる
The two are destroyed
壊せる
I can break it
壊せない
I can't break it
狂える
I can go crazy
狂えない
I can't go crazy
あなたを汚せないよ
I won't let you be tainted
揺れて歪んだ世界にだんだん
In this swaying, distorted world,
僕は
I'm gradually...
透き通って見えなくなって
becoming transparent and invisible
見つけないで
Don't find me
僕のことを見つめないで
Don't gaze at me
誰かが仕組んだ孤独な罠に
In this lonely trap someone set
未来がほどけてしまう前に
Before the future unravels
思い出して
Recall
僕のことを
For who I am
鮮やかなまま
As vivid as can be
忘れないで
Don't forget me
変わってしまったことにパラライズ
Paralyzed by the fact that things have changed
変えられないことだらけのパラダイス
A paradise filled with things that can't be changed
覚えていて 僕のことを
Remember me
教えて
Tell me
僕の中に
Inside of me
誰かいるの？
is there someone else?
残響散歌 / 作詞：aimerrhythm 作曲：飛内将大
Zankyou Sanka / Lyrics: aimerrhythm Composer: Masahiro Tobinai
誰が袖に咲く幻花
Ephemeral flowers blooming on someone's sleeve
ただそこに藍を落とした
Just left a trail of indigo there
派手に色を溶かす夜に
On a night when colors melt away flashily
燦然と輝く月を添えて
Accompanied by the brilliantly shining moon
転がるように風を切って
Cutting through the wind as if rolling
躓くごとに強くなった
Becoming stronger with every stumble
光も痛みも怒りも
Light, pain, and even anger
全部抱きしめて
Embrace it all
選ばれなければ 選べばいい
If you aren't chosen, then just choose for yourself
声をとどろかせて
Let your voice roar
夜のその向こうへ
To the other side of the night
涙で滲んでいた あんなに遠くの景色まで
To the scenery so far away, once blurred by tears
響き渡れ
Resonate far and wide
何を奏でて
What are you playing?
誰に届けたくて
Who do you want to reach?
不確かなままでいい
It's okay to be uncertain
どんなに暗い感情も
No matter how dark the emotions
どんなに長い葛藤も
No matter how long the conflict
歌と散れ 残響
Scatter with the song, resonance
ただ一人舞う夜
Just dancing alone through the night
違えないタイを結べば
If we tie a bond that never fails
手のひらの中強欲に
Greedily in the palm of my hand
深紅の過去さあ暴れ
Now, let the crimson past run wild
この先どんな辛い時も
No matter how painful the times ahead may be
口先よりも胸を張って
Hold your head high instead of just making excuses
抱いた夢の灯を全部辿るだけ
Just trace all the lights of the dreams you held
逃げ出すためここまで来たんじゃないだろう？
You didn't come all this way just to run away, did you?
選ばなければ選ばれればいい
If you don't choose, you should just be chosen
声を枯らして燃える花のように
Like a burning flower with a withered voice
闇間を照らしたら
If I light up the darkness
曖昧すぎる世界も鮮明にして
I'll make even this world that's far too vague clear
夜を数えて朝を描くような
Counting the nights and painting the morning
鮮やかな音色を鳴らす
I'll make a vibrant melody ring out
どんなに深い後悔も
No matter how deep the regret
どんなに高い限界も
No matter how high the limit
掻き消して 残響
Drown it out, echo
ねぇ、見て
Hey, look
ほら、早く
Come on, hurry up
(C-020)
「もうやめてよ！」
'Stop it already!'
もうやめてよ！
Stop it already!
(C-022)
「ん、おいしい！食べてみて！」
'Hmm, delicious! Try it!'
ん、おいしい！食べてみて！
Hmm, delicious! Try it!
ねえ。
Hey.
もう、終わりにしない？
Shouldn't we end this already?
(C-052)
「あなたのことが、」
'I’ve always...'
あなたのことが、ずっと...
I’ve always...
(C-071)
「ずっと、好きでした」
'...liked you.'
好きでした。
...liked you.
別世界
作詞・作曲:天音かなた 編曲:Numa
Another World
Lyrics/Composition: Amane Kanata, Arrangement: Numa
作文の空白を埋めるみたいに
Like filling in the blanks of an essay
一日をただ過ごした
I just spent my day
僕はまた狭い部屋で膝抱き寄せて
In my cramped room again, I hug my knees
笑えるほど何度も何度も
Time and time again, it’s almost laughable
あなたを想った
I thought of you
笑顔も声も愛も口癖だって
Your smile, your voice, your love, even your favorite phrases
見てるだけでいい そう思っていたのに
Just watching you is enough, or so I thought
愛してくれ 僕のことを
Please love me
どうか邪魔などしないから
I promise I won't get in your way
消せない写真と目合わせて
Locking eyes with the photos I can't delete
笑ってくれ 僕のことを
Please laugh at me
あなたには届かないけど
Even though my voice won't reach you
酷く焦がれる恋をしてた
I was in a love that burned so deeply
混ざることない指 息を止める
Fingers that will never intertwine, I hold my breath
名も無い僕は客席の中
Me, with no name, among the audience
舞台の二人ただ見つめて
Just staring at the two of you on stage
今知らないあなたがまた増える
Now, there’s more of you that I don’t know
僕もまた肥大した心が醜く溢れた
And my own heart has become bloated and overflowed hideously
目配せの意味 揃いの仕草だって
The meaning of a glance, even our matching gestures
額縁の中さ 無様に手を伸ばして
Within the picture frame, I pathetically reach out my hand
気付いてくれ 僕の声に
Please notice my voice
「片想いみたいだ」だなんて
Saying something like, 'It's like an unrequited love'
そんな綺麗なものじゃないや
It's not something as beautiful as that
そんな綺麗ごとのじゃないや
It's not that simple, or that pretty
届きやしない歌　独り踊る
A song that doesn't reach, I dance alone
たとえばそう　あなたがそう　ぼくのことをしらなくても
For example, even if you... didn't know about me
ずっとすきでいてもいいですか
May I love you forever?
でもあなたが　いらないなら
But if you don't need it
このおもいが　いらないなら
If you don't need these feelings
いきを止めてしまいたい
I want to stop breathing
愛してくれ　僕のことも
Please love me, too
どうか邪魔などしないから
I won't be in your way
遠い遠い別世界で
In a world far, far away
袖触れないままに　幕が上がる
The curtain rises without even touching sleeves
ただ　また会いたくて
I just... wanted to see you again
あなたにこの拍手を
And give you this applause
はい！ということで
Yes! So
やっとみんなにお届けすることができやした
I finally got to share it with everyone
1年前のあの特報、みんな覚えていますでしょうか
The special news from a year ago,
do you all remember it?
あのですね、あの、回々奇譚やドラマツルギーなどの
編曲をなさっている
Well, the person who did the arrangements
for "Kaikai Kitan" and "Dramaturgy"...
NumuA-sanというね、お方に編曲をしていただいて
A person named NumuA-san provided the arrangement
天音かなた作詞作曲のオリジナル曲「別世界」
今回初披露できました
And I was able to perform my original song "Bessekai"
for the first time, which I wrote and composed
みんなありがとー！
Thank you everyone!
ということでですね、そしてたくさんのね、曲を歌って
And so, after singing many songs...
そしてそして、なんといってもこれだよね、みんな
And then, most of all, it's this, right everyone?
新衣装です！
A new outfit!
こちらですね、100万人記念で運営さんに
作っていただきました
The management made this
for my 1-million subscriber milestone
ありがとうございます
Thank you very much
ちょっと歌うときに着る衣装っていうことで
It's an outfit specifically for singing
おしおママに仕立てていただきました！
Oshio-mama designed it!
可愛い衣装！
It's such a cute outfit!
ということでですね
And so...
えーみんな、もう1曲やっぱりあの曲歌っておかないとっていうのがあるよね
Everyone, there's one more song that I absolutely
have to sing, right?
ということで、あの曲を歌いたいと思います
So, I'd like to sing that song
そしてその後にはですね、あのグッズの紹介もございますので
And after that, I'll also be introducing
some merchandise
と、あ、そうだそうだ、そういえば
And, oh right, that's right, now that I think about it
今日はもう1回、最後にお着替えを用意しているんでした
I've prepared one last outfit change for today
ということで、あのちょっとお着替えしたいと思います
So, I'm going to change my outfit a bit
そしてステージもですね、ちょっとこっちに移動したいと思いますので
And I'll also be moving the stage over here
それじゃ、いくか！
Well then, let's go!
みんなもお揃いの服持ってるはずだから、着とけよ
You all should have the same clothes too, so put them on
ということで、じゃ、みんな、移動するよ
Alright, everyone, let's move
ほいっ！
Hoi!
「特者生存ワンダラダー！！」作詞・作曲：田淵智也
Survival of the Fittest Wonder-der!!
Lyrics/Composition: Tomoya Tabuchi
な、
Na...
ぬ、びし、
Nu, bishi...
おりゃ、だし、
Orya, dashi...
過ごしたい本日快晴
I want to spend today in high spirits
さわ、ぽろ、ぎゅむ、
Sawa, poro, gyumu...
バキ、
Baki...
手に入れる全部いつ舞い暮れ
I'll get it all, whenever the day ends
適当に頑張ろっか
Let's just do our best
そんなんだっていいけどさ
That's fine and all, but
必死に頑張ろっか
Let's give it our all
それが僕らしいよな
That's just like me, isn't it?
挫折しちゃねえんだわ
I'm not giving up
そんで貧乏してねえんだわ
And I'm not broke either
運命がバッチリいけてるに決まってる！
Destiny is definitely on my side!
かなだーちゃん
Kanata-chan
どどん！前進上等、ちゃんと歓迎して
Dodon! Charging forward, welcome it properly
たったいま、海空創造、ちゃんと享受して
Right now, creating the sea and sky, enjoy it properly
興奮しよお
Let's get excited
僕が言うんだもん
Because I'm saying it
本当にするんだもん　現実越えの未来
I'll really make it happen, a future beyond reality
あー！
Ah!
弱点も平気スイッチでらっちゃー！
Even my weaknesses are fine, switch on!
すなわち特者生存ワンダランデイ
Namely, Survival of the Fittest Wonder-land Day
楽しもお
Let's have fun
おもしろがれること探しだまえ　おた！
Search for something interesting, okay!
返事聞かせてくれ
Let me hear your answer
右左なんかじゃない
It's not about right or left
決めつけて一直線
Decide and go straight
つまり企んだら発射
In other words, once you've planned it, launch
まいーたワクワクすんぜ
I'm getting excited
みんな、新曲「別世界」のMVはこのあとすぐに
Everyone, the MV for my new song "Bessekai"
will be out right after this
かなたんチャンネルで投稿予定でございます！
on Kanatan Channel!
ぜひぜひ、たくさん聴いて、いっぱいっぱい歌ってください！
Please, listen to it a lot and sing it a lot!
「何だよそんなこと」
What is that?
言っちゃダメだ おバカ
You're not supposed to say it, you dummy
わあ、すごい！ありがとう！
Wow, amazing! Thank you!
日々 go これ、全力のウェイ
Every day, go this way with all your might
虎視眈々でいたいなもんだって
I want to be vigilant, always watching for my chance
意気揚々がいいなもんだって
I want to be in high spirits
不意にガッツリ焦ってハッピーなんじゃん
Getting all flustered suddenly is happy, isn't it?
いつでも心はちゃんと純粋で
I want my heart to always be pure
いたいな 好奇心は絶えず熱心で
and my curiosity to be constantly eager.
いたいなって 言い聞かせんだ
That's what I tell myself.
調子に乗ったらすぐ飽きられちゃうから
Because if I get carried away, people will soon get tired of me.
あー
Ah—
タイトなロープもどんとこいですぜ
Even a tightrope walk? Bring it on!
すなわち特者生存ワンダーランデー
In other words, it's a "Special One Survival Wonderland Day"!
しがみつけ
Hold on tight!
努力とは最後まで諦めないこと
Effort means not giving up until the very end.
メモっておいて
Take a note of that.
ホントは baby 自信なんかないよ
To be honest, baby, I have no confidence at all.
ホントは baby 不安ばかりで泣きそう
To be honest, baby, I'm so full of anxiety I feel like crying.
でもね baby 挫けないで決めたんだ
But you know, baby, I've decided not to give up.
だから baby 挑戦したいよ
That's why, baby, I want to take on the challenge
未開の地 無限のフィールド
of uncharted territories and infinite fields.
前進上等 ちゃんと還元して
Moving forward is best, giving back properly
高まれ 好奇創造 ちゃんと共鳴して
Soaring high, creating curiosity, resonating truly
興奮しよう
Let's get excited!
僕が呼んだもん 本当にするんだもん
Since I'm the one who called it, I'm going to make it real.
現実超え未来へ
Go beyond reality towards the future.
あー 逆転も兵器 スイッチ入れちゃえ
Ah— reversals are weapons too, flip the switch!
すなわち特者生存ワンダーランデー
In other words, it's a "Special One Survival Wonderland Day"!
楽しもう
Let's enjoy it!
面白がれること探し放題ですぜ
There's no limit to the fun things we can find!
無限のフィールドで
In the infinite field,
パニックしなくてもいい ど真ん中で
no need to panic, right in the center!
つまりこれが僕の答えなんだ
In short, this is my answer.
胸を張れ 今を生きるその意味を
Stand tall and confirm the meaning of living in the now,
明くる日も明くる来る日も確かめ進め
day after day, day after coming day, and move forward.
おらあ！
Oraa!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
3周年記念ライブ、楽しんでいただけたでしょうか？
Did you enjoy the 3rd Anniversary Live?
今回もグッズが登場いたします！
Once again, new merchandise is here!
グッズは4種類ございまして、アクリルスタンド、タンブラー、
There are four types of goods: an acrylic stand, a tumbler,
お守り、ラバーコースターとなっております。
a charm (omamori), and a rubber coaster.
そして今回も、グッズのフルセットをご購入いただいた方には
And again, for those who purchase the full set,
購入特典のポストカードと特典ボイスが付いてきます。
there's a bonus postcard and special voice lines.
今回も直筆サイン数量限定なんですが、
The hand-signed version is limited in quantity,
書かせていただきますのでよろしくお願いいたします。
but I'll be signing them, so please look forward to it.
アクリルスタンドは、うなぽっぽ先生に描いていただきました。
The acrylic stand was illustrated by Unapoppo-sensei.
とっても素敵なイラストとなっております。
It's a very lovely illustration.
ぜひぜひデスクなどに置いてください。いつでもかなたんと一緒です。
Please display it on your desk. You'll always be with Kanatan.
えーそしてお守り、こちら双葉はる先生に描いていただきました。
And the charm was illustrated by Futaba Haru-sensei.
うぱもいるこの可愛いお守り、どこに付けてもあなたを守るはず。
With Upa on it, this cute charm will protect you wherever you go.
えーそしてタンブラー、こちらですね、とっても大人っぽいデザインにしていただいたので、
As for the tumbler, it has a very mature design,
職場でも学校でも使えると思われます。
so it's perfect for use at work or school.
そしてこのパッケージ、めちゃかっこいいです。
And the packaging is incredibly cool too.
そしてタンブラーの下に敷くのはラバーコースター。
To go under the tumbler, we have a rubber coaster.
これでどれだけ結露しても大丈夫、デスクは汚しません。
No matter how much condensation there is, your desk will stay clean.
こちら3周年記念のフルセットはなんと、なんとお値段6000円となっております！
The 3rd Anniversary Full Set is available for just 6,000 yen!
そしてそして、フルセットの購入特典はこちらでございます。
And here are the bonuses for the full set purchase.
数量限定バージョンは直筆サインと箔押し複製メッセージ入りポストカードと特典ボイス。
The limited version includes a signed postcard with a foil message and voice lines.
そして普通のフルセットの方は、
And for the regular full set,
箔押し複製サイン＆メッセージ入りポストカードと特典ボイスとなっております。
it includes a foil-stamped signed postcard with a message and voice lines.
ということで皆さん、天音かなた活動3周年記念のグッズもよろしくお願いいたします。
So everyone, please check out Amane Kanata's 3rd anniversary merchandise!
そしてこの後は、新曲「別世界」のMVが投稿されます！
And after this, the MV for my new song 'Another World' will be posted!
こちらのMVマジでめっちゃ動くからよろしくお願いいたします。
The animation in this MV is truly incredible, so please check it out.
プレミア公開このまま飛べるんで、絶対見てください！
You can jump straight to the premiere, so please don't miss it!
そしてその後、22時15分からメンバー限定配信でアンコールライブやりますので、
After that, from 22:15, I'll be doing a members-only encore live stream.
そちら気になる方はぜひメンバー入って一緒にライブの余韻楽しもうよ！
If you're interested, please join and let's enjoy the afterglow together!
ということで今回もありがとうございました、天音かなたでした！
That's all for today, thank you very much! This was Amane Kanata!